[Music]
[音乐]
this is nick with logosbynick.com and in
我是来自logosbynick.com的尼克
this tutorial i'll be demonstrating how
在本教程中，我将演示
you can take a vector object and apply
您可以获取一个矢量对象并应用
this very quick and simple sketch effect
这种非常快速而简单的素描效果
to it using the hatches path effect in
使用中的阴影路径效果添加到它
inkscape
墨迹
so to get us started here i'm going to
所以为了让我们从这里开始，我要
apply this effect to a really simple
将此效果应用于非常简单的
shape first so let me get this out of
先做好形状，让我把这个拿出来
the way i'm going to grab the circles
我要抓住圆圈的方式
and ellipses tool and i'm going to click
和省略号工具，我要点击
and drag on the canvas to create a
并在画布上拖动以创建
circle like that i'll hold ctrl to make
这样的圆圈，我会按住Ctrl键来做
this perfectly round
这个完美的圆
so i'm going to apply the sketch effect
因此，我将应用素描效果
to this shape and then we'll go ahead
到这个形状，然后我们继续前进
and apply it to some text
并将其应用于一些文本
so the first thing we want to do is open
所以我们要做的第一件事就是开放
up the path effects menu so i'm going to
在路径效果菜单上，所以我要
come up here to where it says path and
走到上面写着路径的地方
i'm going to click on path effects
我要点击路径效果
and you're going to get this little menu
你会看到这份小菜单
over here in the right hand side of the
在这里的右手边
screen and what we're looking for down
屏幕和我们在下面寻找的东西
here is where this little plus icon is
这就是这个加号小图标的位置
you click on that to add a new path
您可以单击该选项来添加新路径
effect and you're going to see you have
效果，你会看到你有
this whole list of different path
这是一系列不同的路径
effects to choose from the one that we
从我们选择的效果中选择
are looking for is right here it's
就在这里，就在这里
called hatches if you're having
称为舱口，如果你有
difficulty locating it you can come up
很难找到它，你可以找出来
here to the search bar and just type in
在这里到搜索栏，只需键入
hatches and there you go there it is
舱口，然后你就到了，就是这样
okay so once we apply that as you can
好的，一旦我们尽可能地应用这一点
see it took the object and filled it
看，它拿起这个物体，填满了它
with these lines otherwise known as
这些线条也称为
hatches and what you can do now is grab
舱口，你现在能做的就是抓起
the edit paths by nodes tool and if you
按结点编辑路径工具，如果
notice let me zoom in on this a little
注意，让我把这个放大一点
bit
比特
if you notice we have these green nodes
如果你注意到我们有这些绿色的节点
right here we have this one green node
在这里，我们有一个绿色节点
and then we have this green node and
然后我们有这个绿色的节点，
then down here we have this yellow node
然后在这里我们有一个黄色的节点
and then we have this yellow node so let
然后我们有这个黄色的节点，所以让我们
me show you how this works this first
我先给你演示一下这是怎么回事
green node right here if you click and
绿色节点就在这里，如果您单击并
drag it it allows you to change the
拖动它，您可以更改
position of the hatches on the object
对象上图案填充的位置
this green node over here allows you to
这里的这个绿色节点允许您
change the density and the direction of
更改密度和方向
the hatches so if i bring the green node
所以如果我把绿色的节点
closer to the other green node it makes
更靠近它生成的另一个绿色节点
the hatches more dense like that so it
舱口更密集，所以它
fills in more of the shape and then if
填充更多的形状，然后如果
you rotate it around like that you can
你可以这样旋转它，你可以
change the direction of it
改变它的方向
so let me place this right about here
所以让我把这个放在这里
over here we have um
在这里我们有这个
this these yellow handles right here
这个黄色的把手就在这里
represent the bend so you what you can
代表弯道，让你尽你所能
do is take this one handle and give this
我要做的就是拿着这个把手，把这个
object a bend like that by clicking and
通过单击并单击来对象这样的折弯
dragging it out like that and this other
像这样拖着它，然后这样拖着
yellow handle represents the start point
黄色手柄表示起点
of that bend so if you were to take this
所以如果你拿着这个
over here notice the two handles are
请注意，这里的两个手柄是
moving together if i put this one over
如果我把这个放在一起的话
here this will be the start point and
这里将是起点和
then over here this will be the end
那么在这里，这将是末日
point and i can move this all the way
波恩特和我可以把这个一直移到
out like that and you can as you can see
就像这样，你可以看到
we are creating quite an intense bend
我们正在创造一个相当强烈的弯道
there so let me put that back towards
好了，让我把它放回去
the original one because i don't want
原来的那个，因为我不想
this to have much of a bend at all i'll
这将会有很大的弯曲，我会
put this back in the center of the
把这个放回中心位置
object and let me zoom out a little bit
对象，让我稍微缩小一点。
i'm going to grab the select tool now
我现在要拿起选择工具
let's say we want to make these hatches
比方说，我们想让这些舱口
thicker or larger what you can do is
更厚或更大的你能做的是
just scale down the object using the
只需使用
select tool i'm going to hold ctrl so
选择工具我要按住Ctrl键
that it scales proportionately scale it
按比例调整比例，调整比例
down like that and as you can see it
就像你看到的那样
makes the hatches bigger if you scale it
如果你缩放舱口，会使舱口更大
down if you scale it up it makes them
如果你把它放大，它会让他们
thinner so let me scale this down a
更薄了，所以让我把这个缩小一下
little bit so i get a nice a nice size
有点，这样我就能得到一个很好的，很好的尺寸
hatch that i like right there that looks
我喜欢的图案就在那里，看起来
pretty good and after you do that you
很好，在你这么做之后，你
may want to edit the um you may want to
可能想要编辑这个您可能想要
go back to the nodes tool and edit the
返回到节点工具并编辑
the density of those hatches as you can
这些舱口的密度
see here make them a little closer
看这里，让他们靠近一点
together like that
就这样聚在一起
and once you're finished applying this
一旦你用完这个，
effect you can finalize it by going to
Effect您可以通过转到
path
路径
object to path
对象到路径
and now that is a vector path and no
现在这是一条矢量路径，没有
longer a path effect
更长的路径效果
okay so that is how you can create that
好的，这就是你如何创建它
simple sketch effect for like a regular
简单的素描效果，就像一个规则
object let me show you how to do this
对象，让我向您演示如何做到这一点
with text now
现在使用文本
i'm going to grab the text tool
我要去拿文本工具
right over here click on the canvas and
就在这里，点击画布
i'm going to write
我要写下
sketch
草图
and i'm going to change the font of that
我要更改它的字体
i'm going to go to text text and font
我要转到文本文本和字体
and i'm looking for
我要找的是
i'm going to use a heavy font for this
我要用大字体来做这个
i'm going to use chunk 5. you can use
我要用第五块。你可以用
whatever font you'd like but i'd
任何你想要的字体，但我会
recommend using a really bold
推荐使用非常粗体的
heavyweight font click apply
粗体字体，点击应用
let me grab the select tool and scale
让我抓起选择工具并进行刻度
this up
这个就起来了
hold ctrl so it locks the proportions
按住Ctrl键以锁定比例
like that
就像这样
now the thing with these path effects
现在有了这些路径效果
with this sketch or this this uh hatch's
用这个素描或者这个呃舱口
path effect it only works on pads it
路径效果它只在衬垫上起作用
won't work on objects that aren't pads
在不是垫的物体上不起作用
this right here is a text object so that
这是一个文本对象，因此
the hatch's path effect won't work on
舱门的路径效果将不起作用
this unless we convert it to a path
除非我们将其转换为路径
so in order to change this from a text
所以为了改变这一点，从一篇文本
object to a path we just select it and
对象添加到一条路径，我们只需选择它并
go to path
转到路径
object to path
对象到路径
and now i can come back up here to my
现在我可以回到我的
path effects menu add that path effect
路径效果菜单添加该路径效果
again there it is hatches
又来了，舱口
and if you notice here there's not much
如果你注意到这里没有太多
visibility there because there's not
能见度在那里，因为没有
much density between those hatches so
这些舱口之间的密度很高
let me zoom in
让我放大一下
let me grab the edit pads by nodes tool
让我来抓取按结点编辑面板工具
and i'm going to take this green handle
我要拿着这个绿色的把手
and bring it towards the original like
并把它带到原来的样子
that and as you can see we are getting
正如你所看到的，我们正在得到
the sketch effect as we intended
如我们所愿的素描效果
there we go that looks pretty good right
我们走吧，看起来不错，对吧？
there now i'm going to zoom out
现在我要把镜头拉近
and to finalize this i will go back to
为了完成这一点，我将回到
the select tool i'll go to path
我要转到路径的选择工具
object to path and there you go now we
反对小路，你现在去吧，我们
have our simple sketch effect that we
有我们简单的草图效果
have created using inkscape
使用inkscape创建
if you found this lesson useful be sure
如果您发现本课有用，请务必
to check out my inkscape master class
查看我的水墨风景大师班
it's a collection of over 60 videos
它包含60多个视频
where i go over all of the tools and
我检查了所有的工具，
features in inkscape just like i did in
inkscape中的功能就像我在
this video and i explain what they are
这个视频和我解释了它们是什么
and demonstrate how they work we even
并演示它们的工作原理，我们甚至
have a private community where you can
拥有一个私人社区，您可以
answer ask questions and get help from
回答问题并从以下人士获得帮助
me anytime you want i'll have a link in
只要你愿意，我都会有一个链接
the description of the video if you want
如果您愿意，可以查看视频的描述
to check that out as always thanks for
一如既往地检查一下谢谢
watching
看
[Music]
[音乐]